Julie Yue

Front-End Developer

Creative and dedicated Front-end Developer with experience designing and developing user interfaces. Efficient self-learner who enjoys working closely with team members to facilitate deliverables. Passionate about expanding my coding knowledge and applying my skills on a talented development team to develop quality solutions.

Work History

2022-01 - present Front-end Developer Intern, React

Growth Acceleration Partners. Austin

- Collaborated with a development team to create an employee profiling dashboard with consistent UI/UX using React, JavaScript, and Redux.
- Designed reusable components using reliable code, connected APIs using Axios, and utilized version control efforts with GitLab and Git Bash.
- Added components and fixed bugs by completing tickets in 2-week sprints and pushing them through code review, QA, and PO review.
- · Created UI for components, adhering to design mockups.
- Implemented error checking and best practices by Typechecking with PropTypes, following ESLint rules, and conforming component design to mockups.

2021-09

- present

Front-end Developer Intern

Growth Acceleration Partners, Austin

- Developed a full-cycle price comparison tool, handling phases from conception to completion by employing APIs, Apps Script, Google Data Studio, and Google Sheets.
- · Enhanced SEO with Yoast, improved UI by adjusting CSS, and fixed bugs using PHP of the WordPress website.
- · Assisted in completing a redesign of existing website to improve user experience, enhance visuals, and strengthen search engine rankings.
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.

Education

2017-08

Computer Science, Bachelor of Science, Expected May 2022

- present University of Texas at Dallas, Dallas

Personal Projects

2021-07 - 2022-03

Personal Website (React) https://julzevias.github.io/julie-yue/

- Developed a React website with three different applications that all integrate HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React.
- Built and solidified React foundational knowledge including combining components with props and hooks, handling events, and implementing dynamic routing.
- · Included various open source components, some of which include reactscroll, styled-components, ityped, and react-icons.
- · Customized an original UI and added libraries and components that enhanced UI and UX.

Personal Info

Email

julie.yue.2011@gmail.com

Phone

512-412-1653

Website

https://julzevias.github.io/julie-yue/

Software

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

React

Jira

Redux

RESTful APIs

C++

Java

Git

Unix Shell Scripts

JQuery

Soft Skills

Problem Solving

Creativity

Communication Skills

Teamwork

Interests

· Produced digital art using graphic tablet, Krita, Photoshop, Illustrator, and InDesign.